indiaclub.com 2011-04-15

# Indiaclub.com - Privacy

---  
| 

**Browse Categories**    
  
**IndiaClub.com Privacy Policy  
**

**1\. The information we collect**

 When you use our site, we receive and collect certain information. The information that we receive and collect depends on what you do when you visit Indiaclub.com. 

  * _Information Collected via Cookies_. We use cookies to enhance the browsing and shopping experience on the Indiaclub.com site. "Cookies" are small files or records that we place on your computer's hard drive to collect information about your activities on the Indiaclub.com site. The cookies transmit this information back to the computers at Indiaclub.com or our third-party distributors of banners and newsletters; these computers are, generally speaking, the only computers which are authorized to read such information. The information captured makes it possible for us (i) to speed navigation, keep track of items in your shopping cart, and provide you with custom tailored content; (ii) to remember information you gave to us so you don't have to reenter it each time you visit the Indiaclub.com site; (iii) to monitor the effectiveness of certain of our marketing email campaigns; and (iv) to monitor total number of visitors, pages viewed, and the total number of banners served. 

 Most people do not know that cookies are being placed on their computers when they visit the Indiaclub.com site or most web sites because browsers are typically set to accept cookies. You can choose to have your browser warn you every time a cookie is being sent to you or you can turn off cookie placement. If you refuse cookies, you will not be able to open a Indiaclub.com Shopping Cart and therefore will not be able to complete an order with us online. Also, by not using cookies, your overall Internet browsing experience will be affected. 

 If you would like to obtain more information about the third-party distributor of banners on the Indiaclub.com site and to know your choices about having such distributor's cookies turned off, please visit [www.privacychoices.org](http://www.privacychoices.org/). If you turn off the third-party distributor's cookies, you will still see banners on our site; however, the banners will not be tailored to your shopping experience.

  *  _Information Collected Using Pixel Tags or Clear GIFs_. To help us understand the effectiveness of certain of our email marketing efforts, Indiaclub.com may use "message format" and "message open" sensing technologies. Both technologies require the use of pixel tags or clear GIFs (also called web beacons). The "message format" sensing technology allows us to recognize whether you have enabled your email program to receive HTML emails; if so, this information is then associated with your email address so that subsequent messages can be sent to you in HTML format. The "message open" sensing technology allows us to recognize whether you have opened our email message. We can only detect this if your have enabled your email program to receive HTML emails.
  *  _Information You Actively Submit to Indiaclub.com_. For most of the browsing services we provide, we neither require nor collect "Personal Customer Information" -- your name, email address, billing address, shipping address(es), phone number and credit card information. You can browse the Indiaclub.com site and take as much time as you want to review our books and other products, services and reviews without having to submit such Personal Customer Information. Even when you use our shopping cart as you browse, there is no need to submit Personal Customer Information. 

 In the following instances, however, we do need you to actively submit Personal Customer Information: when you want to (i) open an account or complete an order, (ii) subscribe to our Newsletters, (iii) subscribe to books of my choice newsletter and other promotions

    * **Creating a Indiaclub.com Account or Completing an Order.** You can create a customer account with Indiaclub.com  to complete an order. To open an account, you will need to create a password-protected account with us. In doing so, we require that you provide us with all of the following Personal Customer Information: your name, email address, billing address, shipping address(es), and credit card information. We use industry standard e-commerce security technology to protect the Personal Customer Information that you transmit to us when you establish your account and each time you access your account information. When setting up the account, we ask you to create a password. When you want to make a purchase or change your stored Personal Customer Information, we approve your access by verifying your email address with your password.
    * **Books of my Choice! Newsletter and Alerts.** You may sign up for free email Newsletters and Alerts filled with recommendations and reviews for books, music, and more.  Such registry is different from the Indiaclub.com Account and password which you set up to make purchases. You can sign up for our Newletter service as either a registered or nonregistered customer of Indiaclub.com . Furthermore, the contact information collected in the Newletter service is only used to forward the Newsletters and Alerts you select.  

**2\. How we use and share Personal Customer Information**

 Occasionally, Indiaclub.com uses Personal Customer Information to market products and services. You can opt-out from us using your information for this purpose at any time by visiting [Unsubscribe](http://www.indiaclub.com/shop/unsubscribe.asp)

 Indiaclub.com shares Personal Customer Information that we collect as follows: 

  * Subcontractors. We send Personal Customer Information to third-party subcontractors and agents that work on our behalf to provide certain services. These third parties do not have the right to use the Personal Customer Information beyond what is necessary to assist us. **They are contractually obligated to maintain the confidentiality and security of the Personal Customer Information and are restricted from using such information in any way not expressly authorized by Indiaclub.com.**
  * Service Providers. We send Personal Customer Information to third-party providers of goods and services that you may purchase from time to time on our site (e.g., music). Like subcontractors, these third parties do not have the right to use the Personal Customer Information beyond what is necessary to assist us. **They are contractually obligated to maintain the confidentiality and security of the Personal Customer Information and are restricted from using such information in any way not expressly authorized by  Indiaclub.com**
  * Credit card companies. Credit card transactions are handled by a third-party financial institution and their vendors, which receive the credit card number and other personal identifying information only to verify the credit card numbers and process transactions.
  * Law Enforcement Investigations. Indiaclub.com may release Personal Customer Information when we believe, in our good judgment, that such release is reasonably necessary to comply with law, enforce or apply the terms of any of our policies or user agreements, or to protect the rights, property, or safety of Indiaclub.com, our users, or others.

**3\. Communications from Indiaclub.com**

 As a customer, you may receive the following communications from the Indiaclub.com: 

  * **Communications related to transaction and account maintenance activities.** These communications include without limitation: order confirmations; order update notices; order problem notices; and notices regarding material changes to site policies and account management procedures.
  *  **Communications containing information about Indiaclub.com and its partners products and services.** We send promotional emails and other outbound communications to Indiaclub.com customers regarding products and services from Indiaclub.com, its subsidiaries and trustworthy third parties. Any Indiaclub.com customer who does not wish to receive such product and service communications can choose to remove his or her contact information from our contact list at any time by visiting [Unsubscribe](http://www.indiaclub.com/shop/unsubscribe.asp)   

  * **Books of my Choice! Newsletter, Alerts, Recommendations.** You may sign up for free email Newsletters and Alerts filled with recommendations and reviews for books, music, and more.  Such registry is different from the Indiaclub.com Account and password which you set up to make purchases. You can sign up for our Newsletter service as either a registered or nonregistered customer of Indiaclub.com . Furthermore, the contact information collected in the Newsletter service is only used to forward the Newsletters and Alerts you select.    

**4\. Underage customers**

Our products and services are marketed for purchase by adults or with the consent of adults. This is why Indiaclub.com requires a credit card that has been authorized for use to complete purchases on our site.

 **5\. Linking to third-party web sites**

 When you click on links and banners on our site that take you to third-party web sites, you will be subject to the third parties' privacy policies. While we support the protection of privacy on the Internet, Indiaclub.com cannot be responsible for the actions of any third-party web sites. We encourage you to read the posted privacy statement of any and every site you visit, whether you are linking from our site or browsing on your own. 

**6\. Changes to Privacy Policy**

 This privacy policy was last changed on July 15, 2004\. Indiaclub.com reserves the right to modify or amend this policy at any time by posting the revised privacy policy on our site. The changes will only affect the information we collect after the effective date of the change to our privacy policy unless we clearly express otherwise. 

**7\. Questions or comments**

 If you have any questions regarding our privacy policy, please [ contact us](http://www.indiaclub.com/shop/contactcenter.asp)
